Hey everyone. In this video, I'll be
showing you a pure 12 build for the
death domain cleric in Boulders Skate 3,
the newest subclass in patch 8. This
gets the touch of death ability at level
two, which lets you spend your channel
divinity to do additional necrotic
damage and attack. Interestingly enough,
if you use the Daredevil gloves, you can
do this on things like bone chill. And
bone chill can attack two targets at
once with our level one ability here.
The reaper lets us target two targets.
And if we have two channel divinities,
we can use the touch of death twice with
the Daredevil gloves, which is kind of
an interesting interaction, but I'll be
going over everything regarding the
death domain cleric here. I would
recommend for the first cantrip that you
get from the death domain to take bone
chill there because we can learn the
other ones here in the U regular cleric
cantrip area. This is where we're going
to grab the dead, one of the best new
cantrips because with this we can target
two targets, but it's also going to do
pretty good damage because it has a
wisdom save making it much more likely
to land than sacred flame. I still like
to take sacred flame for the radiant
damage as there's some targets in act
two that take double damage. Bursting
sineu is nice, but I like to always have
guidance prepared. So, I think these
three worked best. Uh, produce flame is
good into the second act. Now, for our
ability scores, I'd recommend if you're
the face of the party, use the hager to
take up to 18. You can start with 17,
but otherwise, I like to go with a stat
spread of something like this. Since we
only get medium armor, we want to have
some decent defenses here. So 16
dexterity, 14 constitution, 10
intelligence, 16 wisdom, and 10
charisma. You can put some of those
points into strength, but I just find
that this works well. And take the skill
proficiency in persuasion if you're the
face of the pity. Otherwise, doesn't
really matter. Level two gives us turn
undead, but the big one is the channel
divinity touch of death. Whenever we do
a melee attack, we use the channel
divinity to do additional necrotic
damage. And what's great is inflict
wounds is a melee attack roll. though
any spell that can do an attack roll if
we do it with the daredevil gloves. This
means if we were to multiclass we could
actually do it on things like scorching
ray which is kind of funny. My
recommended spells to grab here would be
sanctuary. I also like to have bless
command and uh we'll take inflict wounds
guiding bolts here just for a bit of
extra radiant damage. It can set up your
other spell attackers and the thing is
it's an attack roll too but the big ones
being sanctuary and command as well as
inflict wounds that kind of works well
on this build. Create or destroy water
is also a good choice if you have a cold
or lightning damage caster because you
can double their damage using this.
Disregard the mods that I have installed
there. Uh but we get blindness and the
ray of infe.
Furthermore, we also get level two
spells which lets us take things like
hold person which I think is a really
good spell setting up our our melee
attackers to get critical hits. This is
a good spell. Use hold person often
because if you land it that targets out
of combat and you're going to do extra
damage against them. Level four gives us
another choice in canrip. We can take
bursting sineu here just cuz it fits
thematically. This isn't as good as corp
explosion and divinity original sin 2,
but it'll do. We also then can take
things like aid. Um I also don't mind
having lesser restoration just for if
you need it. But our first feat I would
recommend alert or a plus two to our
wisdom score there. That's probably the
best too. Or caster also has some merit
as it'll help us hold our concentrations
which we're going to be holding as we
hit level three or five here because
this gives us access to spirit guardians
which is an incredible spell and there's
a necrotic version once we hit level six
that is honestly not bad too. The thing
is we also get animate dead which can be
good. This will make an enemy or raise
it undead that will help tank for your
team and vampiric touch will actually
proc our channel divinity. The only
problem is you recover half the health
points. Those extra damage points you
get from the touch of death do not
contribute to this. Not really that
great unfortunately. So I still even in
my previous builds I posted to death do
I mean I don't use vampiric touch that
much. It's okay just okay at best. We
still don't mind going into too melee
range cuz spirit guardians is such a
good spell. And I also recommend
grabbing glyph of warning. This is like
a short-range fireball or lightning
ball. And the thing is, if you're a half
elf or an elf, you can use the sleep one
and you're immune to sleep, which is
actually really good for setting up your
teammates because they'll get critical
hits off on the attacks against the
targets and you can just drop it at your
feet if you get surrounded. Level six
gives us inescapable destruction. It's a
cool name. Gives it the ability to
ignore resistance to necrotic damage.
That's good because there's actually
quite a few things that are resistant to
it in the game. Now, for our next spell,
I'd recommend grabbing, massing word is
nice or revivify. I like mass healing
word especially if you have any of the
gear that lets you apply uh buffs on
your heels like the ring you get from
Vololo the whispering promise. But once
we get to level seven we get another
good spell here with blight. This will
give us an 88 of necrotic damage and
ignores resistances. What's good is
there's a lot of plants that are
actually uh so plants will take maximum
damage from this. But a lot of the
plants that we do end up finding in the
game are actually resistant to necrotic
damage. So we can actually use this with
this subass. We also get death ward,
which is nice to have, and level four
spells. Banishment's a pretty good one.
Guardian of faith can give you a big
tanky uh tank that'll basically give us
uh 60 extra health to work with to
protect our team with. Once we get to
level eight, we get the divine strike
necrotic. And this is really interesting
because we can use an offhand crossbow.
If you're playing as a drought, you'll
get the the crossbow proficiency, but
offhand crossbow let you actually proc
this ability. It's kind of nice. For our
next feed at level eight, I'd recommend
boosting our wisdom score up to 18. or
if you've already done it, up to 20.
Level 9 gives us the cloud kill spell,
which is great if we're using undead.
And you can also use heroes feast to
make your entire team immune to cloud
kill, which is cool. And contagion. We
also get some fun spells here with like
insect plag, which can be really useful
for locking down an area with difficult
terrain. It is a high cost of level five
spell slots, same as flame strike, which
are not ideal, but I mean, they work.
You could also grab the maskear wounds
if you want. And if you're wondering
these, this is the succubus spells
version two by Freya. Once we get to
level 10 here, we got a divine
intervention and we can take another
cantrip resistance or produce flame
being good choices. And then for our
next prepared spell, plan our binding
can sometimes come in handy. It's
actually a fun spell to use. Not the
best, but it's a fun one. Level 11. This
is actually when we get our best spells
cuz we get planer ally. This is crazy
because the genie is super super good
with the thunderwave push back. It's
crazy. We also get heroes feast at this
level which is nice because basically
whenever you pop this you can have
everyone hang out in cloud kill and not
have to worry. It also gives your team
more health. It's it's a really good
one. 12 extra health points. Wisdom
saves with advantage. What more can I
say? Heal and blade barrier fun and heal
actually has a cool interaction with the
dark urge. So I'd recommend you try that
out. Level 12 for our final spell that
we'll prepare. Heal is nice in a panic
if you need it or blade barrier but I
think heal kind of gets the edge. And
for our ability score improvement, I
would recommend just going with wisdom
increase. Another fun one is dual
wielder and using two staves. If you
don't have someone using Mara Heshker,
you have to have someone for the chain
lightning. I'd recommend this character.
Lucky for the luck points can also be
pretty effective on this type of setup.
I also like to go with something like
the war caster to give advantage on
saving throws to hold your
concentrations as that just means that
we're going to be keeping our spirit
guardians up longer. But you can get the
amlet of greater health to give you that
same benefit. So I'm going to go with
the increased wisdom for better spell
casting. And as far as gear goes, we
actually have some pretty solid options
here. Now, medium armor, the armor of
agility will give us the highest
possible armor class. We got that up to
a 23 there. Pretty nice. This is without
any of the extra gear. That would give
us like a plus five to armor class. So,
yeah, that's a good option. Now, I
personally prefer with all clerics to
run the armor, luminous armor. This is
crazy because every creature that gets
hit with radiant damage in a 3 m radius
will get two rounds of radiating orbs.
This becomes crazy when we pair this
with a bunch of other things that we can
hit a bunch of extra radiant damage on,
like the callus glow ring, which will
add two points of it when we're
illuminated. The coruscation ring, which
can give us radiating orbs whenever we
uh deal spell damage. Kind of crazy. And
then we also have the luminous gloves.
Whenever we deal radiant damage, the
target receives two turns of radiating
orbs. So, we create an area of effect,
which we'll apply to other targets.
We'll apply two turns with that. And
then when we cast a spell, we can also
apply two turns and we can get two
points of radiant damage on anything
that we do. We also got the Holy Lands
helm here which will apply 1d4 radiant
damage when attacker misses us with an
attack. So it keeps the radiating orbs
on the target. I also have the
vivaceious cloak here which will give us
eight temporary health points after
casting a spell within melee which can
work especially well with the uh
daredevil gloves which gives us the plus
one spell attack rolls. And your melee
your range attacks spell attacks are
made as melee spells when you're
adjacent to a hostile creature which
kind of cool. I'm actually going to put
this on for the purpose of this build uh
just to showcase the cool ability as
this is an item that very uniquely
interacts with the death domain cleric.
But uh this will also pop the vivacious
cloak, give us a bit of extra tankiness
and we still got all of our debuffing
from luminous armor. The boots of storm
and clamor is also great because this
will apply two turns of reverberation.
It's great. And for rings, I also have
the ring of regent free action here so
we don't get slowed down when we're
running around with spirit guardians. We
basically can't be stopped. But another
good choice is to go with the callus
glow ring which will add two points of
radiant damage which again will proc our
gear which is good. The cortisation ring
will also go radiating orbs on the
enemy. And we got the staff of cherish
necromancy here. So this will give
enemies disadvantage on saving throws
against necromancy spells. Now the life
essence harvest makes things like circle
of death actually pretty decent because
you can hit a huge area of effect spell
with that. Unfortunately this doesn't
really work as well as with this setup
but it's still a strong option. and it
gives us a free blight if we wanted it
and the targets will have disadvantage
on the save. I also have Viconia's
walking fortress, the hell rider long
bow for the plus three to our initiative
and amulet of greater health. Although
you can use the amulet of devout though
that's probably the best choice for an
extra channel divinity and a plus two to
spell save DC. I should also mention the
whispering promise is a very early game
item that can get blessed on people that
you heal which is also a really good
option. And then you can also go with
something like the um reviving hands to
get blade ward and death ward or the
hell rider's pride if you're in act one.
Now if you know you're getting into a
fight, you can throw spear guardians up
early. Another fun option if you want to
hold a concentration on something. Cloud
kill. After using heroes feast, this can
do some pretty crazy stuff because with
the cloud kill, you can just camp out
and the targets will be taking damage.
Although poison damage is often
resisted, not a terrible option, but
spirit guard is just way better. And
we're going to go with the radiant
version because it's going to give us
the all the debuffs on the enemies to
apply radiant orbs with. So, we want to
go with that because yeah, it's also
going to give us uh some stacks of
reverberation on the enemy, too. So,
you're just basically going to be
running around with this trying to pick
off as many enemies you can with it.
Setting up the radiating orbs as you do.
So, if you proc an opportunity attack,
that's okay. You can see there with a
miss, we're actually able to apply more
radiating orbs and we were actually able
to do reverberation for some thunder
damage. But uh yeah, the spirit
guardians is nice cuz sometimes you can
get lucky with some explosion explosive
stuff like that. Uh but yeah,
positioning is huge when it comes to
spirit guardians cuz you can just
sometimes do some crazy stuff. And with
the daredevil proximity, what's funny is
then it gets us the ability to use bone
shill at melee range. Unfortunately, it
has to have two targets that are right
beside each other to be able to do the
double version of that. But you can see
here we can go ahead, we can get a crit
off on that and we can also use the
touch of the death on top of it. If it
was wasn't going to take the target, it
would have there. So that's how you can
do bone chill on a touch of death
combination. And having sanctuary is
also nice for the bonus action. If you
need to shut down and protect someone,
you can also do that. And the best thing
is planer ally here gives us the genie,
which is great because we can use this.
Unfortunately, I can't shove anyone off
of ledges here, but it still does a good
amount of damage. 12 and 23 there. And
then you got the shifting wind. So it
actually has some pretty crazy mobility.
It's got movement speed and it can zip
zap and zoom across the battlefield just
like that. Into our second turn, we
don't have to set up spear guardians
boost. So, we got a lot more damage that
we can do. We basically want to be
running around applying radiator orbs as
much as we can cuz sometimes you can get
lucky with that. But that target now is
10 turns of radiating orbs uh because of
the area of effect that we get from our
uh ability there. And what's funny is
you want to sometimes proc those
opportunity attacks cuz you can actually
make the targets take damage from that.
Now, we also have things like blight,
which are nice cuz it's normally not
that powerful, but it's going to ignore
resistances and it's kind of one of the
better necrotic damage attacks we got.
You saw there okay damage. It's not the
best, but not the worst either. Uh, we
also have things like the bursting
sineu, which are kind of fun cuz you can
use this to explode corpses if they're
not too damaged there. Uh, we only got
one that we can do here, so it's not
ideal, but that's a fun one. Also,
having command is really effective
because with this, we can basically just
lock down the large group of enemies all
at once. And we'll go ahead. We'll only
do it on four targets here, but we're
able to get it landed on a few of them.
And, uh, it also applies reverberation,
which is kind of funny. And what's great
about that is they're going to walk into
our spirit guardians here. We also got
the mass healing ward if we need to be
able to apply a heal to a group of our
teammates, which is kind of nice, too.
So, yeah, we'll just let everyone a
little run towards us basically. And our
genie might be able to get a knock out
here. Unfortunately, had shadow heart,
but she was stuck against the wall, so
she got knocked and he was able to take
them out. And then you can see they're
walking towards us, which proxs the
opportunity attacks. I like command
approach. As you can see here, it does
some pretty crazy stuff. Three of them
just exploded. Command gravel. Might be
able to get another. Ah, we got hit with
the gravel. Unfortunately, the only
downside is not having counter spell
means that our our spells go down
quickly. And since we don't have spirit
guardians up now, I can show you that
cloud kill is also kind of a funny one.
It's got a large area of effect. You can
see that poison damage and those enough
to also knock them prone, which is kind
of funny from the reverberation. But
since we have the uh thoroughly stuffed,
we aren't going to be getting hit with
that. And the targets just going to be
knocked prone there. They're the last
targets. So, we can also then just go
ahead with our blade spell to likely
finish them off here. but otherwise they
would get hit with the cloud peel and
take the poison damage. So yeah, very
powerful combination. It's cool to be
able to use that daredevil proximity to
get our channel divinity touch of death
off on targets. Uh you can also do that
with things like vampiric touch, but I
prefer a double bone chill on two
targets is actually pretty crazy damage.
So let me know your thoughts in the
comments. Hit the subscribe button below
if you enjoy.